<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>p-value | AKitsche Blog</title>
    <link>/tag/p-value/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/p-value/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>p-value</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© 2021 Andreas Kitsche</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_2.png</url>
      <title>p-value</title>
      <link>/tag/p-value/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alternative effect size measurements corresponding to the two sample t-test</title>
      <link>/project/effect_size/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Dec 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/effect_size/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If interest is in comparing the means of two (normally distributed) samples it is common practise to perform a two-sample t-test and report the corresponding p-value. Nevertheless, it has been widely criticized that the p-value does not provide a measure for the magnitude of the mean effect (e.g., Browne (2010)). This report provides an overview of existing alternatives recently published in the scientific literature that provide a more meaningful measurement of the effect size. Browne (2010) introduced closed form equations to translate a significant t-test p-value and sample size into the probability of one treatment being more successful than another on a per individual basis. This term was afterwards denoted as win probability by Hayter (2013) and he demonstrated the interpretation as &amp;ldquo;what would happen if a single future observation were to be taken from either of the two treatments, with attention being directed towards which treatment would win by providing the better value.&amp;rdquo; In addition Hayter (2013) introduced the corresponding confidence interval as well as the odds of X being greater than Y. He further introduced the transformation into Cohens effect size and the corresponding confidence intervals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You can find the pdf of a detailed article &lt;a href=&#34;/files/pdf/effect_size.pdf&#34;&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
